\[Resolved\] Trimble-Wide Notification: Ongoing Service Disruptions

|

|

My Account

Back

Back

Sign In[Create account](https://id.trimble.com/ui/sign_up.html)

Explore Trimble

* [Trimble.com
    
    ](https://www.trimble.com/)
* [Our Industries
    
    ](https://www.trimble.com/en/solutions/industries/overview)
* [Trimble Community
    
    ](https://community.trimble.com/home)

Search all Trimble sites

SketchUp, Trimble, and Your Privacy
===================================

As part of Trimble, we are dedicated to keeping your data private and secure. We are also committed to transparency, so we want you to understand the information we may collect from you and why we collect it. The following is a supplement to [Trimble’s privacy commitment](http://www.trimble.com/privacy.aspx).

The information we collect falls into three categories:

**Purchase Information**

When you purchase or use one of our free products, we collect basic information provided by you to ensure a record of your purchase and entitlements.

**Usage Information**

We capture information that helps us understand your experience with SketchUp, so that we can offer you more helpful content to help you get better at the software you're working with. We do use some of this information to serve you applicable content through digital advertising, email, and web properties.

**Profile Information**

We store information you provide to us to maintain a profile associated with your Trimble account. We use this information to communicate with you, and we never share it with third parties unless you explicitly ask us to, helpful content to help you get better at the software you're working with, and you will always have the ability to update, remove, or add information as desired.

You can always manage your [SketchUp privacy preferences](https://privacy.sketchup.com/), and below you’ll find a more detailed look at how our products and services utilize your data.

* * *

### SketchUp Pro

#### What we collect

SketchUp Pro validates the software license at the time of installation, and collects activation details when the product starts up. The activation details provide anonymized information regarding the environment the application is running in. Specifically, we capture the following:

* Globally unique user ID - Completely anonymous
    
* License state - Trial vs Purchased
    
* Basic product information such as version, operating environment, language, and OpenGL version

Network versions of SketchUp Pro also collect information to make sure that the software is used in compliance with the number of licenses purchased. If, for example, a user purchased a network license with 200 seats, we will count how many seats are currently being used and will allow 200 clients to runs concurrently.

SketchUp Pro uses third-party software to collect error and crash information. The collection and submission of data is voluntary and you will be asked whether or not you would like to submit the information at the time of the crash.

SketchUp Pro relies on Trimble ID for authentication and does not store any user information within the product. Trimble ID collects your first and last name, and email address. This information is required to utilize any products which require authentication (sign in).

#### How we use that information

The metrics are anonymous and we use the data to validate software use and prevent piracy. We also use them to understand product usage and to improve the product’s performance.

#### How to access, update, and protect information

You can access your license information from the SketchUp menu bar. Updates to licenses must be made through the [help of a customer service representative](https://help.sketchup.com/en/contact/customer-support) in order to protect the validity of the license. You may also review your license through our [license manager](https://www.sketchup.com/en/license/renew).

You can find supplemental product specific terms in the [SketchUp Pro end user license agreement](https://www.sketchup.com/en/license/f/sketchup).

#### SketchUp Pro and V-Ray integration

V-Ray® is a plug-in developed by [Chaos Group](https://www.chaosgroup.com/) and used to render photorealistic visualizations. The plug-in is bundled with the SketchUp Studio subscription offering exclusively. SketchUp will share personally identifiable information with Chaos Group if you choose to use the V-Ray extension. The use of the V-Ray plugin conforms to [Chaos Group’s privacy policy](https://www.chaosgroup.com/privacy).

Chaos® and V-Ray® are registered trademarks of Chaos Software OOD in Bulgaria and/or other countries.

* * *

### SketchUp Free

#### What we collect

SketchUp Free relies on Trimble ID for authentication and does not store any user information within the product. Trimble ID collects your first and last name, and email address. This information is required to utilize any products which require authentication (sign in). SketchUp Free also relies on Trimble Connect for project management and file storage. Learn more about [Trimble Connect.](http://connect.trimble.com/) Please see the [Trimble Connect terms of service](https://community.trimble.com/termsandconditions) for more information.

SketchUp Free collects usage information, such as user activity, performance metrics data, and log information, which includes IP addresses, browser type, and error and crash information.

#### How we use that information

SketchUp Free uses the Trimble ID service to validate the use of our free product and to link you to your Trimble Connect account. The metrics are anonymous and we use them to understand product usage and to improve the product’s performance.

#### How to access, update, and protect information

You can access your account information by logging onto the SketchUp Free application and clicking on the preferences button in the top left hand corner of the page. To delete your account, please use the [delete your data form](https://privacy.sketchup.com/).

You can find supplemental product specific terms in the [SketchUp Free Terms of Service](https://app.sketchup.com/tos.html).

* * *

### SketchUp for Schools

This SketchUp for Schools Privacy Notice for Children (“Children’s Privacy Notice”) supplements the [Trimble Privacy Notice](https://www.trimble.com/en/our-commitment/responsible-business/data-privacy-and-security/data-privacy-center/privacy-notice) by providing additional information about how we process the personal information of children under the age of 13 and student users of SketchUp for Schools at a K-12 educational institution (collectively “children”).

This Children’s Privacy Notice sets forth:

* The categories of children’s personal information (“CPI”) that we receive.
    
* How we use the CPI we receive.
    
* Our practices for disclosing CPI.

Most Trimble websites, products and services (“applications”) are primarily designed for adults. We refer to applications designed for adults as “general audience applications.” We do not knowingly collect personal data from children in connection with general audience applications. Certain Trimble applications are appropriate for and are intended for use by children. We refer to these applications as “children’s applications.” At this time, SketchUp for Schools is Trimble’s only children’s application.

Where there is a conflict between this Children’s Privacy Notice and the Trimble Privacy Notice, this Children’s Privacy Notice sets the standard for how we treat CPI, consistent with applicable law.

If we discover that we have processed CPI in a manner inconsistent with applicable law, we will promptly delete the data or bring that processing into compliance with applicable law, such as by obtaining appropriate permission for that processing.

We only access as much information about a child as is reasonably necessary for the child to use the children’s applications. We do not condition a student’s participation on the disclosure of more CPI than is reasonably necessary and we do not store any CPI.

**What we access**

Access to the children’s applications is only available through an integration with either Google for Education or Microsoft for Education (each a “Login/Storage Provider”). A K-12 educational institution (“Educational Institution”) that wants its students to use the children’s applications must have a valid account with the Login/Storage Provider (“Service Account”). Likewise, each of the Educational Institution’s students and other permitted users (i.e. administrators) must have a valid Service Account to access the children’s applications.

Students will log in through their Service Account and SketchUp may access and use the child’s first name, last name, email, Login/Storage Provider username and profile picture, which CPI is hosted by the Login/Storage Provider and provided to SketchUp via the integration with the Login/Storage Providers. We do not store any CPI nor transmit any CPI to third parties. For more information, please visit the [SketchUp for Schools Offering Terms](https://www.sketchup.com/en/edu-tos).

We also use technology to automatically collect information from our users, including children, when they access and navigate through the children’s application and use certain of its features. The usage information we collect through these technologies may include information about actions that users take, where users are geographically located, and the devices and operating systems used (“Usage Data”). The Usage Data is anonymized and not able to be linked to an individual.

**How we use that information**

We use the CPI specified herein to:

* Perform account authentication; and
    
* Provide access to and functionality within the children’s application.

We use the Usage Data we collect automatically through technology to improve our children’s applications, perform analytics and understand product usage and performance. We may disclose Usage Data to third parties.

We do not share, sell, rent, or transfer any CPI to third parties.

**How to access, update, and protect information**

We understand that the security of your data is important. We provide reasonable administrative, technical, and physical security controls to protect user data. In addition, SketchUp for Schools does not store any CPI. Data requests, including requests for access, deletion, or correction, must be submitted to [Google for Education](https://edu.google.com/workspace-for-education/editions/education-fundamentals/) or [Microsoft Education](https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/education), as applicable.

* * *

### SketchUp Viewer

#### What we collect

In order to download SketchUp models on mobile devices, headsets, and other compatible hardware, SketchUp Viewer allows users to sign in to 3D Warehouse, Trimble Connect, Dropbox, the iOS Files App, and/or other applications.

SketchUp Viewer does not store any personal information within the product, other than IP addresses. SketchUp Viewer for Quest specifically, stores additional personal information, such as the Meta User ID, Oculus username and profile photo.

SketchUp Viewer collects usage information, such as user activity, performance metrics data, and log information, which includes IP addresses, device IDs, device type, error and crash information.  

#### ARCore

ARCore is Android's SDK for Augmented Reality which allows you to view your models in AR in SketchUp Viewer. For further information about ARCore privacy practices, please read its [privacy policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/).

#### How we use that information

The metrics are anonymous and we use them to understand product usage and to improve the product’s performance.

Personal information stored in the SketchUp Viewer for Quest application are used to link the user’s Meta or Oculus account with their Trimble ID, and/or enable platform-specific features.

#### How to access, update, and protect information

You have direct control over which cloud services SketchUp Viewer has access to, to sign out from a cloud service click on your Account icon on the top right corner of the page from within the application and select “Sign Out”. To delete a model from the application, on the Home Screen, select the Information icon > Delete on the model you wish to delete.

You can access your account information by logging onto [www.sketchup.com](http://www.sketchup.com/), clicking on your Account icon on the top right corner of the page, and selecting [“Manage my Account”](https://ecom-prd.trimblepaas.com/account/organization). To the extent SketchUp Viewer stores any personal information, to request the deletion of such personal information please use the [delete your data form](https://privacy.sketchup.com/).

Here's how to find supplemental product specific terms:

* HoloLens: within the application, go to Main Menu > Legal > EULA
    
* iOS and Android: within the application, go to Main Menu > Legal > EULA -or- [view the terms online](https://www.sketchup.com/en/license/b/sketchup-mobile-viewer).

* * *

### 3D Warehouse

#### What we collect

[3D Warehouse](https://3dwarehouse.sketchup.com/) allows you to upload, download, and view 3D models. You can keep models private or share them with the 3D Warehouse user community. 3D Warehouse stores the models for you, allows you to comment on models of others and to manage access to your models. 3D Warehouse relies on Trimble ID for authentication. A 3D Warehouse profile is created for you when you log in with Google or Trimble ID for the first time. You can choose to add information about yourself or not. This information can include an avatar, first name, last name, websites you own, and social media accounts. You have the ability to opt in to notifications through your profile. Your profile information is stored within a 3D Warehouse database and is never shared with third parties.

You have the ability to upload your models and make them available for download by the 3D Warehouse community, or keep them private and not accessible by the community. Models shared on 3D Warehouse can be downloaded and saved by community members onto their personal computers or devices. You have the voluntary ability to claim credit for a model by assigning your name or user handle to the model. Once the model is shared, your claimed credit can not be removed from the computers of other users who subsequently downloaded the models.

In addition to your model and profile information, 3D Warehouse collects usage information, such as user activity, for example content likes, view and downloads, performance metrics data, and log information, which includes IP addresses, and browser type.

#### How we use that information

We use your account to associate 3D models to you. You choose to provide the information that you want. You can also choose to keep your information private and only viewable by you. Your account allows you to interact with the 3D Warehouse community, comment, share and collect work, if you choose to do so.

We also track anonymous usage metrics to understand product usage and improve product performance.

#### How to access, update, and protect information

You have direct control of your personal information via the 3D Warehouse profile. To access it, log onto the [3D Warehouse](https://3dwarehouse.sketchup.com/?login=true) and click on the profile icon in the top right corner of the web page. To delete your account, please use the [delete your data form](https://privacy.sketchup.com/).

You can find supplemental product specific terms in the [SketchUp 3D Warehouse terms of use](https://3dwarehouse.sketchup.com/tos).

* * *

### SketchUp Extension Warehouse

#### What we collect

The [Extension Warehouse](https://extensions.sketchup.com/) allows you to upload, download and purchase SketchUp extensions. There are two types of users of the Extension Warehouse, those that download extensions, and those that develop extensions. Users are required to login to download or develop extensions. The Extension Warehouse relies on Trimble ID for authentication. You can choose to add profile information, such as a bio and photo, or not. You have the ability to opt-in to notifications through your profile. Your profile information is stored within the Extension Warehouse website and is only shared with extension developers if you require support for one of their extensions.

SketchUp collects additional information from extension developers. The extension developer [terms of service](http://extensions.sketchup.com/developer-terms-of-service) can be found online. Extension developers can make extensions available for free through the Extension Warehouse, sell their extensions through the Extension Warehouse, or make the extension available on the Extension Warehouse, but collect payment through their website.

The Extension Warehouse collects usage information, such as user activity, performance metrics data, and log information, which includes IP addresses, browser type, and error and crash information.

#### How we use that information

If you purchase extensions through the Extension Warehouse, we will collect billing information necessary to process an order. We use your account to associate extensions to you. You choose to provide the information that you want. You can also choose to keep your information private. Your profile allows you to interact with the Extension Warehouse community, comment, share and collect work, if you choose to do so.

#### How to access, update, and protect information

You have direct control of your personal information via the Extension Warehouse profile. To access it, log onto the [Extension Warehouse](https://extensions.sketchup.com/) and click on the profile icon in the top right corner of the web page. To delete your account, please use the [delete your data form](https://privacy.sketchup.com/).

You can find supplemental product specific terms in the [SketchUp Extension Warehouse terms of use](https://extensions.sketchup.com/en/legal).

* * *

### SketchUp.com

#### What we collect

The SketchUp.com website provides information on SketchUp-related products and links you to other SketchUp services. On the SketchUp website, you can opt-in to newsletters which include marketing materials and tips on how to use SketchUp products. If you download a SketchUp trial, you will be asked to provide some basic information such as first name, last name, email address, company, country and province where you work. You can opt-out of marketing emails when you provide your information. If you are outside of the United States, you can ask to have your information forwarded to a local reseller that can help you with SketchUp products. SketchUp.com uses web browser cookies to remember information about your visit, like your preferred language and your page view history.

#### How we use that information

Information gathered during SketchUp trials is used to provide you information regarding SketchUp products. If you are a user outside the of United States, and you requested to have a local reseller contact you, we will share your name, email address and company information with the reseller.

The cookie information we collect can make our site and products more useful to you. We also use this information to serve you ads relevant to SketchUp on other websites and social networks.

The SketchUp website also collects usage information, such as user activity, performance metrics data, and log information, which includes IP addresses, browser type, and error and crash information.

#### How to access, update, and protect information

You can opt-out of marketing email by clicking on the unsubscribe link included in all SketchUp marketing emails. You can also visit the [unsubscribe page](https://www.sketchup.com/en/contact-us/preference-center). If you wish to delete account, product or support information, please use the [delete your data form](https://privacy.sketchup.com/). You can opt out of ads we show you by interacting with them directly, or by setting your cookie preferences on SketchUp.com to turn off targeting cookies.

* * *

### SketchUp Forums

#### What we collect

The SketchUp Forum is a place to share SketchUp experiences, ask questions, and fix problems through ongoing conversation. In order to participate, users need to create an account. A profile is created for you when you create a SketchUp Forum account and you are able to choose how much information you’d like to disclose. You will also have the ability to opt-in to notifications through your profile. Your profile information is stored within the Forums website and is never shared with third parties.

The SketchUp Forum website collects usage information, such as user activity, performance metrics data, and log information, which includes IP addresses, browser type, and error and crash information.

#### How we use that information

We use your account to associate your conversations and posts to you. You choose to provide the information that you want to share. You can also choose to keep your information private. Your profile allows you to interact with members of the SketchUp community and comment, if you choose to do so.

#### How to access, update, and protect information

You have direct control of your personal information via the SketchUp Forum profile. To access it, log onto the [SketchUp Community Forum](https://forums.sketchup.com/) and click on the profile icon in the top right corner of the web page. You can delete your account directly from your account preferences page.

* * *

### SketchUp Help Center

#### What we collect

The SketchUp Help Center allows you to find answers to questions around the use of SketchUp products; questions about purchasing and billing; and technical support. If you submit a support request, we will collect basic information about you such as your name and email address so that we can contact you.

#### How we use that information

If you submit a support request, you will be assigned a case number and the support request will be tracked to completion in out support system.

The Help Center website collects usage information, such as user activity, performance metrics data, and log information, which includes IP addresses, browser type, and error and crash information.

#### How to access, update, and protect information

If you wish to delete support requests that you have submitted in the past, please use the [delete your data form](https://privacy.sketchup.com/).

* * *

### Sefaira Website

#### What we collect

The Sefaira.com website provides information related to Sefaira products and allows you to opt-in to newsletters which include marketing materials and tips on how to use Sefaira products. If you request a Sefaira trial, you will be asked to provide some basic information such as first name, last name, email address, profession, company, and country where you work.

Sefaira uses cookies to remember information about your visit, like pages visited. That allows us to understand usage of our website and whether users can readily find important information.

#### How we use that information

Information gathered during the Sefaira trial request is used to create a 30-day Sefaira application account. If you opted-in to marketing emails, information regarding offers and tips on using Sefaira products will be sent to your email address.

Cookie information is used for many purposes. They are used, for example, to remember preferences, to count visitors to a page, or to help you sign up for Sefaira services.

The Sefaira website collects usage information, such as user activity, performance metrics data, and log information, which includes IP addresses, browser type, and error and crash information.

#### How to access, update, and protect information

You can opt-out of marketing email by clicking on the unsubscribe link included in all Sefaira marketing emails. You can also visit the [subscription management page](https://www.sketchup.com/en/products/sefaira). If you wish to delete account, product or support information, please use the [delete your data form](https://privacy.sketchup.com/).

You can find supplemental product specific terms in the [Sefaira Terms of Service](https://www.sketchup.com/en/products/sefaira).

* * *

### Sefaira Applications

#### What we collect

The Sefaira web application is the website that runs the performance analysis of your model. Users are required to login in order to use the application. A user profile is created for you when you are added to a Sefaira account as a trial user and/or by your account administrator. We capture basic information about you such as your first name, last name, email, and password. You have the ability to opt-in to notifications through your profile. Your profile information is stored within the Sefaira application and is never shared with third parties.

In addition to your profile information, Sefaira collects usage information, such as projects you own or have access to, user events (e.g. the uploading of models, number of analysis run by users, performance metrics data, and log information, which includes IP addresses, and browser type).

#### How we use that information

The information allows us to understand the usage of the product, and helps to guide the development of new functionality. It also enables us to help you use the product better. Your profile information is never shared with third parties.

#### How to access, update, and protect information

If you wish to delete your Sefaira account, please use the [delete your data form](https://privacy.sketchup.com/).

You can find supplemental product specific terms in the [Sefaira Terms of Service](https://www.sketchup.com/products/sefaira).
